Register of the Yale Brozen papers
Hoover Institution Archives
Yale Brozen papers
1942-1988
Brozen, Yale, 1917-
80119
Hoover Institution Archives Stanford, California 94305-6010
9 manuscript boxes (3.8 linear feet)
Speeches, writings, correspondence, and course materials related to economic theory, economic conditions in the United States, and governmental economic policy.
Administrative Information
Access
Collection is open for research.
The Hoover Institution Archives only allows access to copies of audiovisual items. To listen to sound recordings or to view videos or films during your visit, please contact the Archives at least two working days before your arrival. We will then advise you of the accessibility of the material you wish to see or hear. Please note that not all audiovisual material is immediately accessible.
Acquisition Information
Acquired by the Hoover Institution Archives in 1980.
Accruals
Materials may have been added to the collection since this finding aid was prepared. To determine if this has occurred, find the collection in Stanford University's online catalog at http://searchworks.stanford.edu/. Materials have been added to the collection if the number of boxes listed in the online catalog is larger than the number of boxes listed in this finding aid.
Related Collections
Milton Friedman papers, Hoover Institution Archives
F.A. Harper papers, Hoover Institution Archives
Fritz Machlup papers, Hoover Institution Archives
Friedrich A. von Hayek papers, Hoover Institution Archives
Benjamin A. Rogge papers, Hoover Institution Archives
Biographical Note
1917 Born, Kansas City, Missouri
1936 A.A., Kansas City Community College
1938 B.A., Massachusetts Institute of Technology
1939 B.A., University of Chicago
1940-1941 Assistant professor of social and physical science, University of Florida
1941-1944 Assistant professor of economics., Illinois Institute of Technology
1942 Ph.D. in economics, University of Chicago
1942-1943 Director, Radar and Telephone Maintenance Training Program, Army Signal Corps
1944-1946 Associate professor, Illinois Institute of Technology
1946-1947 Associate professor of economics, University of Minnesota
1947-1957 Professor of engineering economics, Northwestern University, Evanston, Illinois
1951 Consultant, President's Materials Policy Commission
1952 Consultant, Antitrust Division, United States Department of Justice
1954 Visiting professor of economics, Sao Paulo, Brazil
1954- Consultant, National Science Foundation
1956-1963 Consultant, State Department
1957-1959 Director, Research Transportation Center
1957-1987 Professor of business economics, University of Chicago
1972- Adjunct scholar, American Enterprise Institute for Public Policy Research
1974 Author, Advertising and Society
1975 Author, The Competitive Economy: Selected Readings
1978 Author, Corporate Responsibility: The Viability of Capitalism in an Era of Militant Demands
1980 Author, Is Government the Source of Monopoly? and Other Essays
1980s Served on President Ronald Reagan's transition team
1982 Author, Concentration, Mergers, and Public Policy Author, Mergers in Perspective
1983- Vice president, Consortium of Governmental Counselors, Inc.
1998 Died
Scope and Content of Collection
The papers document the career of economist Yale Brozen, who was a professor of business economics at the University of Chicago from 1957 to 1987. In addition to his professorial work, Brozen was a member of the Mont Pèlerin Society and served as a consultant to various government organizations and companies. The collection contains materials related to economic theory, economic conditions in the United States, and governmental economic policy.
The Correspondence mainly contains Brozen's outgoing letters, which include his comments on the writings of others and discussions of various economic issues. Brozen corresponded with several American Enterprise Institute (AEI) scholars, such as Robert Helms and Marvin Kosters. Other correspondents include Ronald Coase, Kenneth Elzinga, David Henderson, Melvin Lurie, and Kenneth S. Templeton.
The majority of the collection consists of Brozen's Speeches and writings, which reflect Brozen's viewpoint as a Chicago school of economics scholar. As an expert on antitrust law, Brozen wrote and spoke about government regulation. His work also comments on the Federal Trade Commission, advertising, and the energy crisis. The collection includes typescripts and printed copies of Brozen's speeches and articles.
The Course materials contain exams for economics and business courses which Brozen taught.
Economics.; Economists.; United States--Economic conditions--1945-; United States--Economic policy.
- Correspondence, 1946-1985 (Box 1-2)
  Scope and Contents note
  Mainly outgoing letters to economists providing comments on the writings of others and discussion of economics.
  - Ambler, Donald, 1946 (Box-folder 1: 1)
  - Arnold, Kenneth, 1974 (Box-folder 1: 2)
  - Bark, Dennis L., 1976 (Box-folder 1: 3)
  - Brunsdale, Anne, 1971 (Box-folder 1: 4)
  - Burnshaw, Stanley, 1946-1947 (Box-folder 1: 5)
  - Cambel, Ali, 1963 (Box-folder 1: 6)
  - Clarkson, Kenneth W., 1974 (Box-folder 1: 7)
  - Clemens, Eli W., 1965 (Box-folder 1: 8)
  - Coase, Ronald, 1974 (Box-folder 1: 9)
  - Cocks, Douglas L., 1974-1976 (Box-folder 1: 10)
  - Coleman, John S., 1953 (Box-folder 1: 11)
  - Cook, Paul, 1976 (Box-folder 1: 12)
  - Dalton, James A., 1971 (Box-folder 1: 13)
  - David, Heather, 1979 (Box-folder 1: 14)
    Includes article adapted from Brozen's speech to the National Association of Manufacturers
  - Davidson, Sidney, 1971 (Box-folder 1: 15)
  - Dean, Joel, 1962 (Box-folder 1: 16)
  - Deans, Robert H., 1970 (Box-folder 1: 17)
  - Demencich, Thomas A., 1970-1971 (Box-folder 1: 18)
  - DeRosa, David, 1978 (Box-folder 1: 19)
  - Dexter, R. D., 1958 (Box-folder 1: 20)
  - Dirksen, Everett, 1952 (Box-folder 1: 21)
  - Douglas, Paul, 1954-1959 (Box-folder 1: 22)
  - Eckert, Ross D., 1971 (Box-folder 1: 23)
  - Edwards, Franklin, 1976 (Box-folder 1: 24)
  - Elzinga, Kenneth, 1976, 1985 (Box-folder 1: 25)
  - Ervin, Spencer, 1980 (Box-folder 1: 26)
  - Ewell, Raymond H., 1954 (Box-folder 1: 27)
  - Fechter, Alan, 1974 (Box-folder 1: 28)
  - Grimaldi, Paul, 1979 (Box-folder 1: 29)
  - Hadley, Don, 1972 (Box-folder 1: 30)
  - Hadley, Eleanor, 1971 (Box-folder 1: 31)
  - Hammond, DuWayne, 1973 (Box-folder 1: 32)
  - Hartzell, Wesley, 1963 (Box-folder 1: 33)
  - Hamilton, W. E., 1958-1964 (Box-folder 1: 34)
  - Helms, Robert B., 1973-1980 (Box-folder 1: 35-36)
  - Henderson, David R., 1977 (Box-folder 1: 37)
  - Henig, Harry, 1953 (Box-folder 1: 38)
  - Hilton, George, 1972-1979 (Box-folder 1: 39)
  - Horsch, Vada, 1962 (Box-folder 1: 40)
  - Huff, Lee W., 1970-1971 (Box-folder 1: 41)
  - Jacoby, Neil H., 1960-1963 (Box-folder 1: 42)
  - Jadlow, Joseph M., 1973 (Box-folder 1: 43)
  - Jamrich, John X., 1966 (Box-folder 1: 44)
  - Jarrell, Gregg A., 1980 (Box-folder 1: 45)
  - Jenkins, H. P., 1958-1959 (Box-folder 1: 46)
  - Jochim, E. W., 1959 (Box-folder 1: 47)
  - Johnson, Thomas, 1983-1984 (Box-folder 1: 48)
  - Johnson, Wilma Ann, 1983 (Box-folder 1: 49)
  - Johnston, James L., 1978 (Box-folder 1: 50)
  - Jordan, William, 1976 (Box-folder 1: 51)
  - Katsh, Salem M., 1982 (Box-folder 1: 52)
  - Kempf, Donald G., 1983 (Box-folder 1: 53)
  - Kosters, Marvin, 1983 (Box-folder 1: 54)
  - Lasagna, Louis, 1972 (Box-folder 1: 55)
  - Lave, Judith, 1973 (Box-folder 1: 56)
  - Lave, Lester, 1973 (Box-folder 1: 57)
  - Lerager, A. J., 1969 (Box-folder 1: 58)
  - Lichtenstein, Charles, 1965 (Box-folder 1: 59)
  - Lindsay, Cotton Mather, 1972-1974 (Box-folder 1: 60)
  - Lobdell, Jared, 1972 (Box-folder 1: 61)
  - Lupton, Daniel, 1969 (Box-folder 1: 62)
  - Lurie, Melvin, 1971 (Box-folder 1: 63)
  - Lustgarten, Steven, 1978-1980 (Box-folder 1: 64)
  - McCraken, Paul, 1980 (Box-folder 2: 1)
  - Meyer, Jack, 1982 (Box-folder 2: 2)
  - Posner, Richard, 1976 (Box-folder 2: 3)
  - Statman, Meir, 1980 (Box-folder 2: 4)
  - Templeton, Kenneth S., 1963 (Box-folder 2: 5)
- Speeches and writings, 1942-1988 (Box 2-9)
  Includes typescripts and printed copies of Brozen's speeches and written works on issues in economics, including antitrust law, government regulation, and advertising.
  - Typescripts, 1942-1988 and undated
    - Affidavit, undated (Box-folder 2: 6)
    - Air and carrier growth articles, undated (Box-folder 2: 7)
    - "The Antitrust Caper: An Appraisal or It's Bad to Be Good", undated (Box-folder 2: 8)
    - "Are FTC Advertising Policies Procompetitive?", undated (Box-folder 2: 9)
    - "Are U.S. Manufacturing Markets Monopolized?", undated (Box-folder 2: 10)
    - "Business Exits, A Source of Efficiency and Flexibility in the American Economy, and Antitrust Law", undated (Box-folder 2: 11)
    - "Capacity, Advertising, and Entry Barriers", undated (Box-folder 2: 12)
    - "Comment on 'The Political Constituency for Antittrust'", undated (Box-folder 2: 13)
    - "Comments on 'Revitalizing the American Economy'", undated (Box-folder 2: 14)
    - "Competition and Prices in the Drug Industry", undated (Box-folder 2: 15)
    - "The Davis-Bacon Act: How to Load the Dice Against Yourself", undated (Box-folder 2: 16)
    - "Economic Policy for the 1970s", undated (Box-folder 2: 17)
    - "The Economics of a National Science Policy", undated (Box-folder 2: 18)
    - "Entry Barriers: Advertising and Product Differentiation", undated (Box-folder 2: 19)
    - "The FTC Attack on Advertising", undated (Box-folder 2: 20)
    - "How Affirmative Is Affirmative Action?" with Laura Genero, undated (Box-folder 2: 21)
    - "Impact of Durability on Sales of a Capital Good", undated (Box-folder 2: 22)
    - "The Impact of Governmental Involvement in Research and Development", undated (Box-folder 2: 23)
    - "The Influence of Engineering Economy Characteristics on Value", undated (Box-folder 2: 24)
    - "Investment, Sunk Capital, and Technological Change," chapter 5, undated (Box-folder 2: 25)
    - "Is Advertising a Barrier to Entry?", undated (Box-folder 2: 26)
    - "Mobilizing Technology for Materials Conservation", undated (Box-folder 2: 27)
    - "Natural Gas Testimony", undated (Box-folder 2: 28)
    - "Net Worth Versus Total Assets", undated (Box-folder 2: 29)
    - "Old Fashioned Nonsense in New Fashioned Dress", undated (Box-folder 2: 30)
    - "Oligopoly in the Petroleum Refining Industry", undated (Box-folder 2: 31)
    - "On the Use and Pricing of Natural Gas for Boiler Fuel", undated (Box-folder 2: 32)
    - "Price, Wage, Rent Controls -- No Way to Stop Inflation", undated (Box-folder 2: 33)
    - "Prospective Industrial Technology and the Labor Force in a Developing Economy", undated (Box-folder 2: 34)
    - "The Purposes of a Price," testimony, undated (Box-folder 2: 35)
    - "Remove Threat to Future Employment from the Gold Drain", undated (Box-folder 3: 1)
    - "The School Finance Problem", undated (Box-folder 3: 2)
    - "Social Implications of Atomic Energy and Technological Change: A Research Planning Report", undated (Box-folder 3: 3)
    - "Socialist Rhetoric vs. Market Realities", undated (Box-folder 3: 4)
    - "Statement by Yale Brozen," speech, American Enterprise Institute conference, undated (Box-folder 3: 5)
    - "Structure of the Petroleum Refining Industry: What Do Concentration Ratios and Gini Coefficients Show?", undated (Box-folder 3: 6-7)
    - Taxes, Tariffs and Farm Prosperity", undated (Box-folder 3: 8)
    - "Technology and the Structure of Society", undated (Box-folder 3: 9)
    - "Trends in the Rate of Return to Capital in the American Economy", undated (Box-folder 3: 10)
    - "Welfare Without the Welfare State", undated (Box-folder 3: 11)
    - "Would Vertical Divestitures Increase Competitiveness or Reduce Prices of Petroleum Products?", undated (Box-folder 3: 12)
    - Some Economic Aspects of Technological Change, dissertation, 1942 (Box 3)
      - Printed excerpt, 1942 (Box-folder 3: 13)
      - Typescript, 1942 (Box-folder 3: 14-15)
    - Minneapolis Economics Round Table, 1946 (Box-folder 3: 16)
    - "The Role of Government in a Democracy," convocation address at St. John's University, 1946 (Box-folder 3: 17)
    - "The Place of Aggregative Economics in Economic Theory", 1948 (Box-folder 3: 18)
    - "The Conservation of Resources," chapter 32, Textbook for Economics, 1948 (Box-folder 3: 19)
    - "Discussion of E. Hoover's 'Capital Accumulation and Progress'", 1949 (Box-folder 3: 20)
    - "Saving and Investment in a Universal Currency System", circa 1949 (Box-folder 3: 21)
    - "Special Problems of the Natural Resources Industries", 1950 (Box-folder 3: 22)
    - "The Economics of Technological Change," speech, Northwestern University, Institute on Contemporary Africa, 1951 (Box-folder 3: 23)
    - "Technological Change in Underdeveloped Areas", 1951 (Box-folder 3: 24)
    - "Economic Progress and Free Enterprise", circa 1952 (Box-folder 3: 25)
    - "Will Decreased Resources Limit Our Standard of Living," speech, Conference of National Organizations, 1952 (Box-folder 3: 26)
    - "Business Outlook and Profits," speech, Label Manufacturers National Association Convention, 1953 (Box-folder 3: 27)
    - "The Economic Outlook", 1953 (Box-folder 3: 28)
    - "Increasing Productivity by Decreasing Trade Barriers", 1953 (Box-folder 3: 29)
    - "National Economic Factors in Business Budgeting," speech, National Society for Business Budgeting, 1953 (Box-folder 3: 30)
    - "The Economics of Material Progress", 1954 (Box-folder 3: 31)
    - "Problems that Face Us", 1955 (Box-folder 3: 32)
    - "Some Tentative Considerations Concerning the Highway Problem", 1955 (Box-folder 3: 33)
    - "The Use of Capital in Developing Areas", 1955 (Box-folder 4: 1)
    - "Scientific Advance as a Factor in Economic Change", 1957 (Box-folder 4: 2)
    - "Statement of Yale Brozen before the Joint Economic Committee", 1958 (Box-folder 4: 3)
    - "Benchmarks for industrial Research (in the Coming Decade)", 1961 (Box-folder 4: 4)
    - Profile of Michigan preface, 1962 (Box-folder 4: 5)
    - "The Role of Cost in the Minimum Pricing of Railroad Services", 1962 (Box-folder 4: 6)
    - Testimony, 1962 (Box-folder 4: 7)
    - Affidavit, 1963 (Box-folder 4: 8)
    - "Causes of High Productivity in the United States," speech, Japan, 1964 (Box-folder 4: 9)
    - "The Economics of a National Science Policy for Japan," speech, Keizai Doyukai, Japan Committee for Economic Development, 1964 (Box-folder 4: 10)
    - "Cartel by Government or Highway Robbery with ICC Assistance," speech, Rockford College, Illinois, 1965 (Box-folder 4: 11)
    - "Education for Responsible Leadership: Major Questions in Economics", circa 1965 (Box-folder 4: 12)
    - "Guidelines and Wage Laws: How Should Wage Changes Be Determined?" speech, Wisconsin Manufacturers' Association, 1965 (Box-folder 4: 13)
    - "The Role of Open Markets in Coordinating and Directing Economic Activity," speech, Future Trading Seminar, Chicago Board of Trade, 1965 (Box-folder 4: 14)
    - "Trends in Transportation," speech, Management Conference on Financial Prospects for Transportation, Northwestern University, 1965 (Box-folder 4: 15)
    - "The Coming Impact of Monetary Policy," speech, Chicago Association of Commerce and Industry, 1966 (Box-folder 4: 16)
    - "The Minimum Wage: Who Really Pays?" interview with Yale Brozen and Milton Friedman, 1966 (Box-folder 4: 17)
    - "On the Value of Division Status Versus Independent Company Status", 1966 (Box-folder 4: 18)
    - "Dismounting From the Tiger," speech, Old Dominion College, Norfolk, Virginia, 1967 (Box-folder 4: 19)
    - "Permanent Prosperity Through Permanent Deficits: The New Mythology of the New Economics," speech, Philadelphia Society, Chicago, 1967 (Box-folder 4: 20)
    - "Current Myths and The Economic Outlook," speech, Financial Prospects for Transportation Conference, Transportation Center at Northwestern University, 1968 (Box-folder 4: 21)
    - "U.S. Monetary Dilemmas: Imaginary and Real," speech, American Society of Real Estate Counselors, Quebec, 1968 (Box-folder 4: 22)
    - "Are These Laws Necessary?" speech, Bishop College, Dallas, Texas, 1969 (Box-folder 4: 23)
    - Testimony prepared for AT&T, 1969 (Box-folder 4: 24)
    - "The Chicago School Vs. the New Economics," speech, Midcontinent Trust Conference, American Bankers Association, 1970 (Box-folder 4: 25)
    - "Down the Collective Bargaining Road to Recession," speech, Wisconsin Manufacturers' Association, 1970 (Box-folder 4: 26)
    - "Ghetto Economics and Policy Implications," speech, Monmouth College, 1970 (Box-folder 4: 27)
    - "Measures for Improving Construction Industry Health," speech, Construction Industry Manufacturers' Association, Chicago, 1970 (Box-folder 4: 28)
    - "The Subtle Suicide of Free Enterprise," speech, Midwest Employers Council, Omaha, Nebraska, 1970 (Box-folder 4: 29)
    - "A Western View of the Economics of a National R&D Policy," speech, economists meeting in Venice, 1970 (Box-folder 4: 30)
    - "Defining and Implementing the Ideal Economic System to Meet Youth's Objectives", 1971 (Box-folder 4: 31)
      Includes correspondence
    - "The Road to Recovery or How Can We Lick a Union Made Recession?" speech, National Wholesale Grocers' Association, 1971 (Box-folder 4: 32)
    - "Statement by Professor Yale Brozen, University of Chicago, on House Bill 003 to Establish a Minimum Wage in Illinois," Illinois Legislative House Committee on Industrial and Labor Relations, 1971 (Box-folder 4: 33)
    - "Who Shot Down the Game Plan?" speech, National Commercial Finance Conference, Chicago, 1971 (Box-folder 4: 34)
    - "The Case for Advertising and Against the FTC", 1972 (Box-folder 5: 1)
    - "The Federal Trade Commission's Iron Curtain," speech, American Advertising Federation, 1972 (Box-folder 5: 2)
    - "In Defense of Advertising," speech, Los Angeles Town Hall, 1972 (Box-folder 5: 3)
    - "An Ivory Tower (Chicago) View of Advertising", 1972 (Box-folder 5: 4)
    - "Productivity: Key to Progress, Role of Capital Formation," speech, Congress of American Industry, New York, 1972 (Box-folder 5: 5)
    - "Regulatory Responsibilities and Opportunities in the 1970s," speech, Symposium on Financial Aspects of Utility Regulation, Stanford University, 1972 (Box-folder 5: 6)
    - "With A Friend Like the FTC, The Consumer Needs No Enemies," speech, Women's Advertising Club of Chicago, 1972 (Box-folder 5: 7)
    - "Economics and Public Policy," interview of Yale Brozen, 1972 (Box-folder 5: 8)
    - "The Fed Has Done It Again!" speech, Management Conference, University of Chicago, 1973 (Box-folder 5: 9)
    - "The Impact of FTC Advertising Policies on Competition," speech, 1973 (Box-folder 5: 10)
    - "Transportation Regulation, Inflation, and the Energy Crisis", circa 1973 (Box-folder 5: 11)
    - "Price Inflation: Causes, Consequences, and Remedies, Income Policies," speech, Conference of the Committee for Monetary Research and Education, 1974 (Box-folder 5: 12)
    - The Competitive Economy, review, 1975 (Box-folder 5: 13)
    - "The Consequences of Economic Regulation," speech, ACU-YAF Conference, Washington, D.C., 1975 (Box-folder 5: 14)
    - "The Road to Recovery or Let's Repeat Our Successes, Not Old Mistakes," speech, Operations Management Conference of the Dealer Bank Association, 1976 (Box-folder 5: 15)
    - "Affidavit of Yale Brozen with Respect to Dealership Contracts for Sale and Service of Motor Vehicles", 1977 (Box-folder 5: 16)
    - "The American Drug Industry: Private Enterprise or Public Utility?" speech, National Coordinating Council for Constructive Action, Los Angeles, 1977 (Box-folder 5: 17)
    - "The Attack on Concentration," speech, Ashland Economic Club, 1978 (Box-folder 5: 18)
    - "The Humphrey-Hawkins Road to Enlarging the Federal Government, Accelerating Inflation, and Reducing the Rate of Economic Growth," speech, Board of Directors of the Chicago Association of Commerce, 1978 (Box-folder 5: 19)
    - "Multinational Corporate Social Responsibilities in Developing Nations," speech, University of Toledo's Hunger Awareness Project, 1978 (Box-folder 5: 20)
    - "The Mythology of Energy," speech, Executive Program Club Alumni School Day, University of Chicago, 1978 (Box-folder 5: 21)
    - "Accelerating Inflation and Sluggish Productivity: Causes and Cures", 1979 (Box-folder 5: 22)
    - "The Attack on Corporate America: The Corporate Issues Sourcebook", 1979 (Box-folder 5: 23)
    - "Commentary on Political Economy," Liberty Fund, Seminar on Political Economy of Antitrust, 1979 (Box-folder 5: 24)
    - "Drugs and Health: What Research Agenda for Public Policy?", 1979 (Box-folder 5: 25)
    - "Forward", circa 1979 (Box-folder 5: 26)
    - "Regulatory Excess," speech, New York University, 1979 (Box-folder 5: 27)
    - "Regulatory Excess and the Energy Crisis," speech, Midewest Planning Association, Chicago, 1979 (Box-folder 5: 28)
    - Testimony before the Subcommittee on Antitrust and Monopoly of the Senate Committee on the Judiciary, 1979 (Box-folder 5: 29)
    - "Why Forecasting the Economy Now Is a Fool's Errand," speech, Home Data Corporation Special Seminar on the 1979 Housing Market, Oak Brook, Illinois (Box-folder 5: 30)
    - Affidavit of Yale Brozen in the case of Independence Tube Corporation v. Copperweld Corporation v. David F. Grohne, 1980 (Box-folder 5: 31)
    - "Economic Challenges of the 1980s," speech, The Oklahoma Economic Conference, Robert Morris Associates, Oklahoma State University (Box-folder 5: 32)
    - "The Economy Today and the Market Place Tomorrow," speech, Senior Executive Program, Blue Cross/Blue Shield, 1980 (Box-folder 5: 33)
    - "Forecasting Business Conditions: Pressures, Pitfalls, and Promises, the Major Pitfall," speech, Graduate School of Business Management Conference, University of Chicago, 1980 (Box-folder 5: 34)
    - "Government Regulation: Its Economic and Political Impact", 1980 (Box-folder 6: 1)
    - "Short Comments on Brozen's Law," interview of Brozen, 1980 (Box-folder 6: 2)
    - "The State's Role in a Changing Economy," speech, Midwest Governors' Conference, Chicago, 1980 (Box-folder 6: 3)
    - "Wage Increases for Federal Works--Are They Justified?", 1980 (Box-folder 6: 4)
    - "Carter's Legacies: Reagan's Promises: The First 100 Days," Associates Program Luncheon, Graduate School of Business, University of Chicago, 1981 (Box-folder 6: 5)
    - "Capitalism and Equality", 1982 (Box-folder 6: 6)
    - "Dealing with Twenty Years of Policy Mismanagement: Reagan's First Year," speech, Ball State University College of Business Business Conference, 1982 (Box-folder 6: 7)
    - "Government and Income Redistribution: Effects on the Private Market," Dr. Scholl Foundation public lecture, Ball State University, 1982 (Box-folder 6: 8)
    - "Mergers and Competition," speech, Institute for American Values, Nichols College, Dudley, Massachusetts, 1982 (Box-folder 6: 9)
    - "Money and Interest Rates," speech, University of Hartford, Connecticut, 1982 (Box-folder 6: 10)
    - "The New Economics Financial Prospects for the 1980s," speech, Mercer University Executive Forum of the Investors' Club, 1982 (Box-folder 6: 11)
    - "Private Enterprise and the Market Economy", 1928 (Box-folder 6: 12)
    - "Strategic Planning and Antitrust," speech, The Conference Board, Antitrust Issues in Today's Economy Conference, 1982 (Box-folder 6: 13)
    - Affidavit of Yale Brozen in the case of S. A. Rouseel-Uclaf against G.D. Searle and Co., 1983 (Box-folder 6: 14)
    - "Antitrust's Rogues Gallery: Rules Without Reason", 1983 (Box-folder 6: 15)
    - Report submitted to the court concerning Daimler-Benz and Mercedes Benz of North America, 1983 (Box-folder 6: 16)